<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software on Struan Clark</title><link>/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in software on Struan Clark</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building an Animatronic Dinosaur</title><link>/post/2019/01/06/animatronic-dinosaur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2019/01/06/animatronic-dinosaur/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of themed entertainment, especially the Disney parks. Theme park rides are some of the most interesting engineering marvels out there and the best part is - you can visit them! For me, the enjoyment of a trip to Walt Disney World comes as much from appreciating the technology and systems used to create rides as it does from the theming and story. A core part of many theme park rides are the animatronic characters that bring the experiences to life. I was recently gifted a Meccano Meccasaur - a toy with some limited &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; functionality. I wanted to see how much I could augment this functionality if I added a new brain and some more points of articulation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Portal Turret Voiced Roomba</title><link>/post/2018/07/15/portal-turret-roomba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018/07/15/portal-turret-roomba/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently replayed the excellent &lt;a href="http://www.thinkwithportals.com">Portal 2&lt;/a> by Valve. One of my favorite things in the game are the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GGPIQ72-2Vg">automatic robotic sentry turrets&lt;/a>. The contrast of their cutesy voices with the fact that they fire machine guns at you on sight makes them a core part of the gallows humor present in the Portal series of games. As I played through the game, I realized that a lot of the voice cues trigger on events that are similar to another robot closer to home - the &lt;a href="http://store.irobot.com/default/robot-vacuum-roomba/">iRobot Roomba&lt;/a> robotic vacuum cleaner. I decided I had to find a way to combine these two things!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>